<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>





<content timestamp="2008-07-15 03:12:23 -0500">





<provider>chicagosports.chicagotribune.com</provider>

<section type="item">





    <item id="41014077" type="article">
	<title>Crede is no A-Rod ... thank goodness</title>
	<url>http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/sports/baseball/whitesox/cs-080714-joe-crede-alex-rodriguez-morrissey,1,43626.column</url>
	
    
	
        <byline>Rick Morrissey</byline>
    
    
	
        <titleline>In the wake of the news</titleline>
    
    
	
        <date>2008-07-15</date>
        
        
    
    
	<body>NEW YORK -- Sitting at a table amid a gob of reporters and cameramen, Alex Rodriguez was talking about his life, which might or might not include Madonna, who, by the way, might be using Jewish mysticism to brainwash A-Rod into thinking the two are &quot;soulmates,&quot; according to friends of Rodriguez&apos;s estranged wife, as reported by the New York Daily News, which keeps track of these things.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;Look, everyone has distractions, everyone goes through personal issues,&quot; Rodriguez was telling the gathered media Monday. &quot;Mine are on the front page of the papers.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
A few minutes later and several tables away, Joe Crede was talking to five reporters about his distractions, which would be &quot;A&quot; material for the cover of Parenting magazine only if he came up with something like a revolutionary toilet-training method.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;The biggest excitement in my life are my two girls, 4 and 2,&quot; he said. &quot;That&apos;s all the excitement I need right there.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Alex Rodriguez, Joe Crede. I always get them mixed up.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
They&apos;re both third basemen. They&apos;re both American League All-Stars. They used to be connected at the agent, Scott Boras, until Rodriguez decided to work out his own deal  last year.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
That would pretty much sum up the similarities between the New York superstar and the White Sox&apos;s resurrected infielder.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This is Rodriguez&apos;s 12th All-Star Game, Crede&apos;s first. Rodriguez is the Yankee with the two-ton contract. Crede is the guy who would like a new contract from the Sox.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The Sox didn&apos;t exactly leave him for dead in the off-season, but they were seen holding a stethoscope. And they sure were talking a lot about an ascendant Josh Fields at third. Whether you believe they were furiously trying to trade Crede and his balky back depends on the person doing the talking.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
But it&apos;s indisputable that Crede is here at the All-Star Game. Sometimes standing still &amp;#8212; or being forced to stand still &amp;#8212; is the best thing for a team.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Forgive Crede for taking some pleasure in this. Thirteen months ago, he couldn&apos;t lift his children because of his back. Six months ago, as he rehabbed from back surgery, he was the subject of trade rumors. Now he&apos;s backing up A-Rod at the All-Star Game.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;As a player you&apos;re always going out there trying to prove everybody wrong, no matter what kind of situation you&apos;re in,&quot; Crede said. &quot;You&apos;ve always got somebody behind you ready to take your spot no matter what your contract status is. You always want to find that way to stay motivated as a player and keep that fire burning underneath you.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 If the Sox are smart, they will work something out with Crede. The All-Star selection would seem to be proof that his formerly aching back isn&apos;t an issue. Aside from a first half uncharacteristically filled with errors, he has been a rock at third base.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 There is the widespread perception in Chicago that Boras is persona non grata with Sox Chairman Jerry Reinsdorf and general manager Ken Williams. Boras insists the reality is completely different.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &quot;Jerry&apos;s a bright guy,&quot; he said. &quot;He&apos;s an easy guy to deal with. ... There&apos;s some draft picks (represented by Boras) that they took that they didn&apos;t sign. That&apos;s just an economic decision.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &quot;I know there&apos;s been some bravado (expressed) by the general manager. But it&apos;s a good place to play, and if my players want to play there, I do everything I can to keep doors open so I can get players where they want to go.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Crede would prefer to stay with the team that drafted him, the team that nurtured him, the team that gave him a chance to win a World Series.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &quot;I think it&apos;s definitely a good possibility,&quot; he said. &quot;It just depends on how things end up this year, how guys develop below you or if there&apos;s trades. There are numerous things that could obviously happen.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &quot;If we happen to fall out of the playoff race or we stay in &amp;#8212; those are two totally different scenarios that could change the outcome for a lot of players.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Even today, fans call the radio talk shows to discuss when Fields will no longer be the third baseman-in-waiting. Crazy talk, but it&apos;s there. Part of it comes from the assumption that the Sox won&apos;t be able to sign free-agent Crede after the season. Part of it comes with the infatuation with the next new thing. Most of it is silly.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 On the other hand, being the subject of silly talk seems a much better existence than having to see your life unfold in the tabloids. On Monday, the New York Post dissed the &quot;paltry&quot; payouts coming from Rodriguez&apos;s non-profit charities.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &quot;The $28 million-a-year Yankee star regularly spends oodles of money on personal pleasures &amp;#8212; including a private plane, a yacht, a waterfront Florida mansion and dozens of other real-estate holdings, as well as scores of lap dances at strip joints,&quot; the Post story said.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Other than that, he&apos;s a regular Joe.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &quot;There&apos;s always been something with me,&quot; Rodriguez said. &quot;I&apos;ve learned to kind of put whatever issues are on the front page in one small box over here, and baseball has been a great vehicle for me to kind of keep my mind on what I love to do most &amp;#8212; play baseball.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &quot;For four hours between those white lines, I get an opportunity to go out and speak with my actions.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 So does Crede. Then he gets to go home to the relative quiet provided by two high-energy little girls.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:rmorrissey@tribune.com&quot;&gt;rmorrissey@tribune.com&lt;/a&gt;</body>

	
	
	<categories>
	   <category>/sports/baseball/whitesox</category>
	</categories>
</item>







    <item id="41014574" type="article">
	<title>Simply  a star searcher</title>
	<url>http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/sports/baseball/cubs/cs-080714-jim-hendry-chicago-cubs-all-stars-rogers,1,6069263.column</url>
	
        <subheadline>Cubs&apos; Hendry has assembled a truly stellar cast</subheadline>
    
    
	
        <byline>Phil Rogers</byline>
    
    
	
        <titleline>On Baseball</titleline>
    
    
	
        <date>2008-07-15</date>
        
        
    
    
	<body>NEW YORK -- Eight isn&apos;t enough for Aramis Ramirez. He believes the Cubs&apos; All-Star roster extends beyond the players who will be introduced with their National League teammates on Tuesday night at Yankee Stadium.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;Jim Hendry&apos;s an All-Star too,&quot; Ramirez said.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Carlos Zambrano agrees. As usual, he expressed his endorsement as only he could.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;I have one word for Jim Hendry,&quot; Zambrano said. &quot;Good job.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Who can argue?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Less than two seasons after  Hendry sweated out a disappointing season that cost Dusty Baker his job and put Hendry&apos;s future in jeopardy, he has become perhaps baseball&apos;s hottest executive&amp;#8212;an overnight success story that was a long time coming.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Hendry&apos;s Cubs reached the All-Star break at 57-38, tied with the Los Angeles Angels for the best record in the majors. They had a club-record eight players elected or named to the NL team, including three veterans (Ramirez, Zambrano and Kerry Wood) who bypassed a crack at free agency because they were happy playing in Chicago. No NL team has had as many All-Stars since the 1960 Pittsburgh Pirates.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
It&apos;s fair to say this is not in keeping with the history of an organization that last won the World Series in 1908 and was the recipient of only 310 of Lou Brock&apos;s 3,023 hits, 25 of Rafael Palmeiro&apos;s 569 home runs and one of Greg Maddux&apos;s four Cy Young seasons.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In the era of free agency, players historically haven&apos;t stayed with the Cubs when they&apos;ve had options elsewhere. Often they have fled, sometimes screaming. But the culture around the franchise has changed in the last decade.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Hendry, a former high school baseball coach who worked tirelessly in the dual roles of scouting director and farm director before replacing Andy MacPhail as general manager in 2002, has had more to do with that change than anyone.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Spending never hurts, and the Cubs have spent more than ever in the last few years. But this change isn&apos;t just about outspending the competition. It&apos;s about people skills&amp;#8212;specifically, creating an environment in which people expect to be treated the right way.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
That&apos;s Hendry&apos;s strength. It has allowed him to build a front-office staff that includes men whose r&amp;#233;sum&amp;#233;s frequently bring them opportunities to go elsewhere. Gary Hughes, Oneri Fleita, Randy Bush, Ken Kravec, Tim Wilken, Chuck Wasserstrom and others&amp;#8212;not unlike Ramirez, Zambrano and Wood&amp;#8212;stay because Hendry makes it fun.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Agent Scott Boras, seen by many executives as a villain because of his ability to extract maximum value for the players he represents, isn&apos;t known to have a great sense of humor. But he couldn&apos;t help but throw in a dig when Hendry&apos;s name came up during a Monday conversation.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;Jim Hendry is, to be totally honest, a [jerk],&quot; Boras said, smiling. &quot;You can tell him I said that.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
It speaks to Hendry&apos;s universally strong rapport that Boras jokes about him. It&apos;s a sign of the respect afforded Hendry at least in part because of his high-energy style.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
His work ethic became legendary when he signed free agent Ted Lilly to a contract while en route to the hospital after a heart episode at the winter meetings two years ago. He has friends in high places, which has allowed him to peek into the Indianapolis Colts&apos; locker room during the Super Bowl and to make occasional trips to Augusta National  (he has broken 80 there).&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Yet he has always been the type of person who takes his work seriously, but not himself. He worked marathon hours while dealing with the pain of a failed marriage and the need to be a strong father for his children. Yet he has never asked for anything more than the chance to keep doing the job he loves.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Zambrano has known Hendry since he was 16 and respects him like a second father. &quot;He is a very dedicated man,&quot; Zambrano said. &quot;When I was young and I did something wrong, I knew he would talk to me. He would take me into an office and talk to me. He would listen to me, and he would talk. He&apos;s a straight guy.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Ramirez wasn&apos;t having a terrific year for the Cubs in 2006 and had let the Cubs know he would probably exercise an early-out clause in his contract. He now says he knew the Cubs wanted to keep him long term because they didn&apos;t trade him when they could have. But he didn&apos;t know if he wanted to stay until he talked to Hendry after the season.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;I had a long talk with Jim before I came back,&quot; Ramirez said. &quot;He told me they were very serious about winning. He told me they were going to go out and get good players. That was important to me. I was 28 and I was happy in Chicago, but I wanted to win. That&apos;s what you play for. Jim convinced me that we were going to have a chance to win.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
On the heels of signing Ramirez to a five-year, $75 million extension, the Cubs gave Alfonso Soriano an eight-year, $136 million contract before the 2007 season. They signed Japanese free agent Kosuke Fukudome for 2008, getting him for less than he was offered elsewhere.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Hughes, Hendry&apos;s top scout, had spent four years building a relationship after falling in love with Fukudome&apos;s talent at the 2004 Olympics. It&apos;s another example of how business is done in Hendry&apos;s front office.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;The team we have reflects Jim and the front office,&quot; said Wood, a first-round draft choice in 1995, when Hendry was the Cubs&apos; scouting director. &quot;They don&apos;t just go get the best players but they get the right players, players who will help you win. They know players, and they know how to deal with players.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;In the 13 years I&apos;ve known Jim, there hasn&apos;t been one time he has told me he was going to do something and not followed up. You respect somebody like that.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Ryan Dempster, a 10-game winner, was a Hendry reclamation project at a time when Tommy John surgery made his future in baseball unclear. He returned the favor by signing a three-year contract when he was healthy.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
They may have a more difficult negotiation after this season, as Dempster should be in demand as a free agent, but it won&apos;t become a contentious one. &quot;Jim&apos;s a special guy,&quot; Dempster said. &quot;He really is. You like dealing with guys like Jim.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Fleita, the Cubs&apos; farm director since 2002, spends countless hours on the telephone with Hendry. Among the things they have discussed: the development of catcher Geovany Soto and the position change for Carlos Marmol from catcher to pitcher. Both are 25 and first-time All-Stars.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Wood appreciates the Cubs&apos; culture change more than anyone.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;When I got to Chicago, fans came to Wrigley Field just to have fun,&quot; he said. &quot;Now they come to see us win. The expectations have changed for the players and for the fans. It&apos;s about winning.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:progers@tribune.com&quot;&gt;progers@tribune.com&lt;/a&gt;</body>

	
	
	<categories>
	   <category>/sports/baseball/cubs</category>
	</categories>
</item>







    <item id="41014823" type="article">
	<title>Ex-Lions RB Jones paying Bears a visit</title>
	<url>http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/sports/football/bears/cs-080714-kevin-jones-chicago-bears-running-back,1,5064385.story</url>
	
    
	
        <byline>By David Haugh</byline>
    
    
	
        <titleline>Chicago Tribune reporter</titleline>
    
    
	
        <date>2008-07-15</date>
        
        
            <time>00:24 -0500</time>
        
    
    
	<body>Really, the Bears have been jonesing for a running game since trading Thomas Jones to the Jets in March 2007, a month after their last Super Bowl appearance.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Can Kevin Jones help supply the potent 1-2 punch that has been missing since then?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Apparently, the Bears are curious enough to take a good look at the ex-Lions running back, a former first-round draft pick who believes he can return to 1,000-yard form after two serious injuries the last two seasons.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 NFL sources said Jones was to take a physical and visit Halas Hall on Tuesday, one week before the Bears open training camp.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
No contract offer has been extended, but if the Bears are satisfied with the condition of Jones&apos; surgically repaired right knee, it shouldn&apos;t be difficult to meet the veteran&apos;s terms. A source said Jones would accept a one-year deal to prove how healthy and effective he still is.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Agent Tony Fleming told the Tampa Tribune late Monday that Jones would sign with the Bears or Steelers on Tuesday. Jones told the Tribune last month that the Bears would be his top choice among potential teams interested in him.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Jones, 25, tore his anterior cruciate ligament Dec. 23, leading to his release by the Lions in March. But he vowed he would return to fulfill the potential he flashed as a rookie in 2004, when he gained 1,133 yards. Injuries to Jones&apos; foot in 2006 and knee in &apos;07 contributed to him gaining only 1,934 yards in three seasons after his rookie year.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Jones staged an impressive workout June 28 to show how quickly he has recovered, and four teams attended the session in Saline, Mich.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The Bears were not among those present. But the team did receive a videotape of the session and kept up with Jones more than they let on after Cedric Benson&apos;s release June 9. Initially, when asked about the possibility of signing Jones before the workout, team sources shot down the idea.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The Bears have faith in second-round pick Matt Forte, but adding a veteran with Jones&apos; potential, even if he&apos;s not cleared until early in the regular season, would decrease the pressure on the rookie. It also would give the Bears two legitimate options at the position, a must for NFL teams thinking playoffs.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
If the Bears sign Jones, it  would  allow Adrian Peterson to return to the special-teams role he starred in during 2006. Adding a fourth running back also would put Garrett Wolfe in a fight for a roster spot.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Signing Jones would represent a gamble. But for a team tired of seeing its running backs losing yards, the Bears have nothing to lose.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:dhaugh@tribune.com&quot;&gt;dhaugh@tribune.com&lt;/a&gt;</body>

	
	
	<categories>
	   <category>/sports/football/bears</category>
	</categories>
</item>







    <item id="41013568" type="article">
	<title>Overseas interest in Cubs not a foreign concept</title>
	<url>http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/sports/baseball/cubs/cs-080714-wrigley-field-sold-chicago-cubs-downey,1,321792.column</url>
	
    
	
        <byline>Mike Downey</byline>
    
    
	
        <titleline>In the wake of the news</titleline>
    
    
	
        <date>2008-07-15</date>
        
        
    
    
	<body>Suppose, just suppose, that Wrigley Field and the Cubs were sold to foreign interests.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Budweiser, king of beers, suds of St. Louis, is in the process of being devoured by another very large brewer, and I don&apos;t mean CC Sabathia.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The Chrysler Building, a true New York giant, a large building of the Big Apple, also has a brand new owner &amp;#8212; a very wealthy one, and I don&apos;t mean A-Rod.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
How about the Cubs?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Suppose a rich bunch of Belgians and Brazilians teamed up to make a bid to Tribune Co. to satisfy a sudden thirst to be Cub men as well as Bud men?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Or suppose a wildly wealthy Abu Dhabi investment group decided to go after a famous little Chicago ballpark built in 1914 the same way it just did a famous New York skyscraper that broke ground in 1928? Would you care?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Does the word &quot;foreigners&quot; scare you? Are you xenophobic? Would your worst fears run amok?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I ask this for no particular reason, other than the obvious one that Euro, Arab and Asian economies could very well be sounder than our own.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
One of these mornings, you will wake up to the news that somebody different owns your &lt;a href=&quot;http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/sports/baseball/cubs/&quot;&gt;Chicago Cubs&lt;/a&gt;. Somebody else will become the curator and caretaker of Wrigley Field, a property decaying so quickly, its head groundskeeper probably ought to be WALL-E.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I honestly don&apos;t know who is going to be the next owner of the Cubs. I only know that they appear to have more bidders than they have All-Stars.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
No inside information has trickled down to me. No one has whispered, &quot;Pssst, Mike, don&apos;t tell anybody yet, but the Cubs are about to be sold to Kim Jong-il.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I wouldn&apos;t be overjoyed to see the team from the North Side end up in the hands of North Korea, but otherwise I really don&apos;t care much who gets it.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I wouldn&apos;t mind if the Cubs get gobbled up by Google.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I wouldn&apos;t mind if Martha Stewart buys the team and plants a row of green beans and summer squash in the ivy.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I wouldn&apos;t mind if the HeadOn &quot;apply directly to the forehead&quot; guys buy the team (because that would suit the Cubs).&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I wouldn&apos;t mind if ExxonMobil buys the park and sells you a beer for five bucks a gallon.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I wouldn&apos;t mind if Starbucks buys the park and opens a new Wrigley Field on every  corner.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I wouldn&apos;t mind if Brad Pitt and Angelina Jolie buy the park and bring in Habitat for Humanity to fix it.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I wouldn&apos;t mind if the Church of Scientology buys the Cubs and makes Tom Cruise so happy, he jumps up and down on his couch.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I wouldn&apos;t mind if Boniva buys the park and changes Wrigley&apos;s name to Sally Field.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
What would I mind?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Oh, obviously, I&apos;d mind if some backstabber like that NBA guy in Seattle comes along to buy the Cubs and moves them to Oklahoma City. There the team&apos;s fans would have to sing &quot;Go, Oklahoma City, Go!&quot; and &quot;My Kind of Town (Oklahoma City Is).&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I wouldn&apos;t want a new owner to get rid of the &quot;W&quot; flags, but he should hang on to the &quot;L&quot; flags &amp;#8212; you know, merely to keep a good team like the Cubs humble.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I wouldn&apos;t want a new Wrigley Field owner to print more ads on the fence, but don&apos;t paint faces on it like the White Sox do. I personally don&apos;t feel a ballpark ought to look as if it were an original LeRoy Neiman.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Nor would I want a new Cubs boss to be a cheap so-and-so.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
After all, according to a database of MLB player salaries, here is what certain Cubbie cash cows will make in 2008 alone: Carlos Zambrano ($16 million), Aramis Ramirez ($15 mil), Alfonso Soriano ($14 mil), Derrek Lee ($13,250,000), Ted Lilly ($8 mil), Ryan Dempster ($7,333,333), Kosuke Fukudome ($7 mil), Jason Marquis ($6,375,000), Mark DeRosa ($4.75 mil), Bob Howry ($4.5 mil), Kerry Wood ($4.2 mil), and Jon Lieber ($3.5 mil).&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Oh, and Geovany Soto, Ryan Theriot and Carlos Marmol should be up for nice bumps.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I can&apos;t wait to see which bidders win and how high or low they go. I wish Bob Barker or Drew Carey could shout, &quot;Come on down!&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The John Canning/Andy McKenna group? The J. Joe Ricketts group? The Thomas Mandler/Jim Anixter group? Don Levin? Mark &quot;Cubbie&quot; Cuban?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
How about Mystery Bidder X?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I wonder if foreign interests could be interested. Anheuser InBev Field. Abu Dhabi Cubbies.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
I don&apos;t think you need to be American to be in the National League.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:mikedowney@tribune.com&quot;&gt;mikedowney@tribune.com&lt;/a&gt;</body>

	
	
	<categories>
	   <category>/sports/baseball/cubs</category>
	</categories>
</item>







    <item id="41014079" type="article">
	<title>&apos;69 game still classic to Santo</title>
	<url>http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/sports/baseball/cubs/cs-080714-ron-santo-1969-all-star-game-mitchell,1,7754823.column</url>
	
    
	
        <byline>Fred Mitchell</byline>
    
    
	
        <titleline>AROUND TOWN</titleline>
    
    
	
        <date>2008-07-15</date>
        
        
    
    
	<body>These Cubs are playing like it&apos;s 1969, and that might not be a dire predicament if they can finish the way they started.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt; Ron Santo &lt;/b&gt;vividly recalls this city&apos;s exuberance when five Cubs headed to the All-Star Game at RFK Stadium in Washington on July 23, 1969.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &quot;We had the whole infield go,&quot; Santo recalled. &quot;It was &lt;b&gt; Ernie Banks &lt;/b&gt;at first, &lt;b&gt;Glenn Beckert &lt;/b&gt;at second, &lt;b&gt;Don Kessinger &lt;/b&gt;at short and me at third. &lt;b&gt;Randy Hundley &lt;/b&gt;was the backup catcher. It was exciting to have that many.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt; Willie McCovey &lt;/b&gt;of the Giants hit two home runs to lead the NL to a 9-3 victory and earn the game&apos;s MVP award.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Santo, the Cubs&apos; radio analyst, was chosen for nine All-Star Games and played in eight of them. He hopes this year&apos;s Cubs contingent enjoys the experience as much as he did.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;I guess the one that really sticks out is my first one, when I was 23 years old ... in Cleveland,&quot; Santo said.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Flamethrower &lt;b&gt;&quot;Sudden Sam&quot; McDowell &lt;/b&gt;of the Indians was the American League&apos;s starting pitcher.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &quot;Can you imagine that?&quot; Santo said. &quot;I knew how hard Sam McDowell could throw. I had faced him in spring training. And he was wild. The guy could throw 98 m.p.h., and he had a big curveball. It was either the first time up or the second time, but I got a base hit up the middle off him.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;When I first got to that All-Star Game, I didn&apos;t feel like I belonged. All the legends of baseball were there &amp;#8212; &lt;b&gt; Willie Mays, Henry Aaron. &lt;/b&gt;When I got that base hit, it was like, &apos;OK, I belong.&apos; The burden of the world went off my shoulders.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Santo was 5-for-15 (.333) in his eight All-Star Games. He has a theory on the only time he didn&apos;t play.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;I feel very strongly that &lt;b&gt; Walter Alston &lt;/b&gt;didn&apos;t care for me,&quot; Santo said of the former Dodgers manager who didn&apos;t use him in the 1964 game.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Santo traced Alston&apos;s enmity to a game earlier that season when he argued a safe call on a rundown play so strenuously that the call was overturned by an umpire with a better view of the play.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;Walter wanted me out of that ballgame,&quot; Santo said with a laugh.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/media/photo/2004-11/15194192.jpg&quot; align=&quot;left&quot;&gt;&lt;b&gt; Overheard:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Cubs Hall of Famer &lt;b&gt; Billy Williams &lt;/b&gt;will never forget his first All-Star Game experience, in 1962. &lt;b&gt;Fred Hutchinson &lt;/b&gt;of the Reds was the NL manager.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &quot;I was sitting on the bench and Hutchinson yelled down to me, &apos;Hey, Williams, go out to left field and pick up Musial,&apos; &quot; Williams said. &quot;I will never forget that moment, subbing for &lt;b&gt;Stan &apos;The Man&apos; Musial. &lt;/b&gt;What an honor.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 Former Cubs trainer &lt;b&gt;Tony Garofalo &lt;/b&gt;has a special memory of &lt;b&gt; Bobby Murcer, &lt;/b&gt;the Yankees broadcaster and longtime player who died of brain cancer over the weekend at 62. Garofalo was in his first year with the Cubs in 1977, the year they acquired Murcer from San Francisco in a controversial trade for two-time batting champion &lt;b&gt;Bill Madlock.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;We were going to be on the Saturday Game of the Week, and Murcer asked me before the game if this was the first time I was going to be on national TV,&quot; Garofalo said. &quot;I told him yes. About the fourth inning he makes a diving catch and he stays on the ground. I go running out to right field to see if he&apos;s injured. When I get there I ask him if he&apos;s OK. He says, &apos;Of course I&apos;m OK, I&apos;m just getting you a little TV time so your folks at home can see you. Now act like you&apos;re doing something.&apos;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &quot;After about two or three minutes he says, &apos;Now get off the field. We have a game to play.&apos; &quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 In the spring of &apos;77, before Garofalo&apos;s family arrived in Chicago, Murcer let him stay in the townhouse he owned in the suburbs until their families got to Chicago.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &quot;When we would go out to dinner, he would always say, &apos;We&apos;ll flip to see who pays,&apos; &quot; Garofalo said. &quot;We would continue to flip until he lost. He was great to me, and I&apos;ll always remember that.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/media/photo/2004-11/15194194.jpg&quot; align=left border=0&gt;&lt;b&gt; Local attractions:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The White Sox gave Northern Illinois University a check for more than $60,000 last week, the proceeds from a game held at U.S. Cellular Field this spring between NIU and Notre Dame, as well funds from auctions at whitesox.com and a donation from &lt;a href=&quot;http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/sports/baseball/whitesox/&quot;&gt;Chicago White Sox&lt;/a&gt; Charities, which will go toward the school&apos;s February 14 Scholarship Fund.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:fmitchell@tribune.com&quot;&gt;fmitchell@tribune.com&lt;/a&gt;</body>

	
	
	<categories>
	   <category>/sports/baseball/cubs</category>
	</categories>
</item>







    <item id="41014826" type="article">
	<title>Sources: Irish to name Indy attorney as AD</title>
	<url>http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/sports/college/notredame/cs-080714-notre-dame-athletic-director,1,3842494.story</url>
	
    
	
        <byline>By Brian Hamilton and Teddy Greenstein</byline>
    
    
	
        <titleline>Chicago Tribune reporters</titleline>
    
    
	
        <date>2008-07-15</date>
        
        
            <time>00:06 -0500</time>
        
    
    
	<body>In its search for a new athletic director, Notre Dame isn&apos;t looking outside the family, but it is looking outside the proverbial box.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The school has zeroed in on Indianapolis attorney Jack Swarbrick as its choice to take over as athletic director, a source familiar with the process told the Tribune.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
While the hiring of Swarbrick might not be an entirely done deal, the announcement of a new AD is expected this week, heralding the end of a process that began with Kevin White&apos;s departure for Duke on June 1.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;We&apos;re not at a point where we&apos;re going to confirm anything,&quot; university spokesman Dennis Brown said Monday.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Swarbrick could not be reached for comment Monday night. He&apos;s a typical choice in one way certain sects of Irish faithful will appreciate: He has an undergraduate degree from Notre Dame (class of 1976)&amp;#8212;a document that for some serves as a passport to acceptance.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In many other ways, the school has opted for a relatively unconventional hire. Swarbrick, a 1980 Stanford law graduate and partner at the Indianapolis firm of Baker &amp; Daniels LLP, has not been an athletic administrator at the collegiate level, though his name has been mentioned in connection with openings at Arizona State, Ohio State and Indiana in recent years.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Swarbrick is, however, well-versed in administration within the athletic realm in general. He was a finalist for the NCAA president&apos;s position that went to Myles Brand in 2002. He was chairman of the Indiana Sports Corp. from 1992-2001, playing a role in moving the NCAA&apos;s offices to Indianapolis. He remains on the sports corporation&apos;s executive committee and board of directors, according to his Baker &amp; Daniels Web site bio.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Swarbrick was a bid committee vice president and sat on the board of directors for Indianapolis&apos; successful attempt to bring the 2012 Super Bowl to Lucas Oil Stadium. He also has served as general counsel for governing bodies of Olympic sports such as USA Gymnastics and U.S. Rowing.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Swarbrick&apos;s one notable misfire of late was as chief executive officer of LMiV, a dot-com launched in late 2000 with the idea of creating a network of Web sites  to allow radio stations to extend relationships with listeners. LMiV&apos;s doors were shuttered  18 months later, with Swarbrick saying in a report on Indianapolis Business Journal, &quot;We just didn&apos;t have a market.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
But another comment in that report suggested Swarbrick had acquired a taste for a leadership role, something that quite clearly would be a prerequisite for the virtual collegiate sports corporation that is Notre Dame athletics, especially its football program.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;This is what I very much enjoy doing, and I hope to continue to do,&quot; Swarbrick said at the time, regarding his stint as CEO. What is most important, indeed, will be Swarbrick&apos;s true place among the leadership of Notre Dame athletics.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
During White&apos;s tenture, Charlie Weis replaced Ty Willingham as football coach and subsequently received a 10-year contract, decisions in which White&apos;s involvement was debatable.Upon White&apos;s departure for Duke, a high-ranking college official told the Tribune that White &quot;was out there with the responsibility but not the authority.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
It will be interesting to see how Swarbrick&apos;s mettle holds up against the various forces that will tug at him as Notre Dame&apos;s new athletic director. Though he did not ascend to the NCAA president&apos;s position in 2002, his comments after the process suggested he was unwilling to be a puppet.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;The one thing I came away from absolutely certain of, because it was important to me and I asked it at every stage, was, &apos;Are you prepared to really have someone lead the organization?&apos; &quot; Swarbrick told SI.com.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;I became very convinced that both at the search committee and executive committee levels they had an absolute desire to make sure they brought in somebody who was prepared to take the initiative to try and lead the association.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Now he&apos;ll have to see if the same holds true at Notre Dame.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:bchamilton@tribune.com&quot;&gt;bchamilton@tribune.com&lt;/a&gt;</body>

	
	
	<categories>
	   <category>/sports/college/notredame</category>
	</categories>
</item>







    <item id="41006007" type="article">
	<title>Favre: Packers should let me play elsewhere</title>
	<url>http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/sports/football/bears/cs-080714-brett-favre-green-bay-packers,1,3475721.story</url>
	
    
	
        <byline>By Chris Jenkins</byline>
    
    
	
        <titleline>The Associated Press</titleline>
    
    
	
        <date>2008-07-14</date>
        
        
            <time>21:58 -0500</time>
        
    
    
	<body>MILWAUKEE -- Brett Favre finally is speaking for himself: He wants to play but doesn&apos;t feel welcome in Green Bay, so he&apos;s asking to be released.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The quarterback&apos;s first substantial comments on his latest retirement decision reversal come in an interview with Fox News on &quot;On the Record with Greta Van Susteren.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;OK, you guys have a different path, fine,&quot; Favre said, recalling a June 20 conversation with Packers coach Mike McCarthy. &quot;What does that mean for me? So that means either you give me my helmet, welcome back, or release me, or attempt to trade me. We all know that&apos;s a possibility, but way-out-there possibility.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;And he says, &apos;Well, playing here is not an option, but we can&apos;t envision you playing with another team, you know, either.&apos; And I thought, so basically, I&apos;m not playing for anyone if I choose to come back.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
According to Van Susteren, who spoke to the AP by telephone Monday afternoon, Favre said he was &quot;never fully committed&quot; to retiring and felt pressured by the Packers to make a decision, a notion Packers general manager Ted Thompson and coach Mike McCarthy tried to dispel in an interview with the AP on Saturday.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;Ted always wanted Brett back,&quot; McCarthy said. &quot;We always wanted Brett back.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The team had no immediate reaction to Favre&apos;s interview Monday.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;We currently have nothing to add on this matter,&quot; a team spokesman said.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Favre told Fox he understands that the Packers want to move on -- but if they&apos;re doing so, they should let him go.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;Them moving on does not bother me,&quot; Favre said. &quot;It doesn&apos;t. I totally understand that. By me retiring March 3, I knew that could possibly happen. All I was saying is, you know, I&apos;m thinking about playing again.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Favre said he has thought about the ramifications of playing for another team, moving to another city, and angering some Packers fans&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;You know, the bottom line is, I may not play anywhere,&quot; Favre said. &quot;But we have thought of all those things. We have thought about it.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Van Susteren -- who is from Appleton, Wis., is a Packers shareholder and previously had interviewed Favre and his wife, Deanna -- said Favre made it clear he would not return to the Packers if he wasn&apos;t the starter. And while Favre said the Packers asked him for a list of teams to which he would accept a trade, he wants to be released to make sure he ends up on a competitive club.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Thompson said the team wasn&apos;t going to release Favre, but he could come back in a &quot;different role than he was&quot; because the team is committed to going forward with Aaron Rodgers.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;You&apos;re telling me playing there is not an option, but playing elsewhere, we just can&apos;t -- we&apos;re trying to protect your legacy,&quot; Favre said. &quot;Well, thank you. I appreciate that. But apparently now, they&apos;re trying to protect my legacy by bringing me back and having me be a backup. Boy, that is really good.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Thompson and McCarthy wouldn&apos;t discuss the possibility of trading Favre and said they hadn&apos;t received any trade inquiries as of Saturday.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Thompson and McCarthy gave AP a detailed description of their dealings with Favre throughout the offseason, including an episode a few weeks after Favre&apos;s retirement where the two were prepared to fly to Mississippi to seal the deal on a Favre comeback -- only to have the quarterback change his mind again.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
In the interview, Favre said the Packers were being dishonest, although he did not point out specific examples in the portion of the interview aired Monday. A second segment is scheduled to air Tuesday.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;If you move on, you tell me one thing, don&apos;t come back and tell the public ... just say it, &apos;You know, we&apos;ve moved on and we&apos;ll work with Brett on whatever it is,&quot;&apos; Favre said. &quot;Don&apos;t make up a lot of stuff or give half of the truth.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
McCarthy and Thompson also expressed concern Saturday that Favre spent most of the offseason questioning whether he still had the commitment to play football. But Favre told Fox News it wasn&apos;t going to be an issue.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;If I&apos;m going to play it&apos;s going to be 100 percent commitment,&quot; Favre said.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Favre&apos;s interview -- which was receiving top billing over an interview with presidential candidate John McCain in promos for Van Susteren&apos;s show that aired during the day Monday -- is the latest development in what is looking more and more like an irreparable schism between one of the NFL&apos;s most storied franchises and perhaps its most beloved quarterback.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Thompson called the situation &quot;gut-wrenching&quot; Saturday.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;I mean, it hurts,&quot; he said. &quot;I&apos;m not talking about physically hurting, but the sensitivity. We understand where the fans are coming from. This is a hot-button issue that surpasses anything I&apos;ve ever gone through.&quot;</body>

	
	
	<categories>
	   <category>/sports/football/bears</category>
	</categories>
</item>







    <item id="41002829" type="article">
	<title>Derrick Rose fined $1,000 for speeding at more than 100 m.p.h.</title>
	<url>http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/sports/basketball/bulls/chi-derrick-rose-plea-webjul15,1,95719.story</url>
	
        <subheadline>Bulls draft pick faces court supervision, online driving course</subheadline>
    
    
	
        <byline>By Cliff Ward</byline>
    
    
	
        <titleline>Special to Chicago Tribune</titleline>
    
    
	
        <date>2008-07-14</date>
        
        
            <time>19:13 -0500</time>
        
    
    
	<body>
 &lt;a href=&quot;http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/sports/basketball/bulls/&quot;&gt;Chicago Bulls&lt;/a&gt; point guard Derrick Rose, the NBA&apos;s No. 1 draft pick, pleaded guilty Monday to speeding and was fined $1,000, placed on court supervision for  6 months and ordered to take an online driving course offered through Kane County.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;I learn from my mistakes,&quot; Rose said after his brief court appearance in Geneva.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Rose, 19, who grew up in Chicago&apos;s Englewood neighborhood, was ticketed April 29 for going more than 100  m.p.h. on  Interstate Highway 88 near Aurora.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Because Rose was clocked at more than 40 m.p.h. over the speed limit, the speeding charge was a misdemeanor. Rose made a &quot;cold plea,&quot; meaning that his attorney, Terry Ekl, and  prosecutors did not negotiate a sentence in advance.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
That left his sentence to the discretion of  Judge Robert Morrow, who said supervision was appropriate, given Rose&apos;s otherwise clean driving record.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;I will give you a chance, sir. It&apos;s in your hands,&quot; Morrow told Rose.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Under the terms of the sentence, Rose&apos;s record will be wiped clean if he does not have any further legal problems for the next six months. The judge also agreed to allow Rose to complete the driver&apos;s course online after Ekl said the traditional classroom course would be difficult given Rose&apos;s travel schedule.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Kane County&apos;s traffic school program is administered through Waubonsee Community College and includes the four-hour online class,  said Karen Herwick of the  county circuit clerk&apos;s office. The county also offers a more extensive six-hour program, which must be taken in person at the college, she said.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Rose, who wore a dark suit and tie to court Monday, said afterward that he was not paying attention to his speed as he drove home to Chicago  the night he was stopped.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;I did something stupid, and I&apos;m just looking forward to the future,&quot; he said.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Rose stopped on his way out of the courthouse to sign autographs for several fans.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Neal Lopez of St. Charles and his son Joel, 13, walked away with a signed basketball. Rose&apos;s indiscretion apparently did not tarnish his reputation with the boy.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;He&apos;s awesome,&quot; Joel said.
</body>

	
        
  		    <image id="41004390" type="photo">
                <url>http://www.chicagotribune.com/media/photo/2008-07/41004390.jpg</url>
                <cutline>Derrick Rose in court</cutline>
                
                    <caption>
The Bulls No. 1 draft pick Derrick Rose enters Kane County traffic court on Monday. He was cited for driving over 100 mph in a 65 mph speed zone on I-88 in April.
</caption>
                
                
                    <credit>Tribune photo by Bill Hogan</credit>
                
  		    </image>
        
	
	
	<categories>
	   <category>/sports/basketball/bulls</category>
	</categories>
</item>







    <item id="41002724" type="article">
	<title>Packer out at CBS; Kellogg takes chair</title>
	<url>http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/sports/college/cs-080714-billy-packer-clark-kellogg-cbs-basketbal,1,3431987.story</url>
	
        <subheadline>Analyst replaced after 34-year Final Four run</subheadline>
    
    
	
        <byline>By Teddy Greenstein</byline>
    
    
	
        <titleline>Tribune staff reporter</titleline>
    
    
	
        <date>2008-07-14</date>
        
        
            <time>21:55 -0500</time>
        
    
    
	<body>NEW YORK -- At the end of a conference call in March, a reporter asked Billy Packer about the rumor that his 34th Final Four would be his last.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Packer cut off the question and said: &quot;My last game will be like my first one. I&apos;ll put a headset on, I&apos;ll take a headset off.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Any idea when that will be?&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;It&apos;ll be when it is,&quot; Packer replied.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
That time is now. CBS announced Monday that Clark Kellogg would replace Packer as its lead college basketball analyst, with former Bulls guard Greg Anthony expected to slide into Kellogg&apos;s studio gig. Though Packer professed not to care what the public thought of his TV work, he wanted it known that he had not been fired.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
An industry source characterized it this way: CBS wanted to promote Kellogg, and Packer agreed not to stand in the way.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;This decision was made with myself and CBS more than a year ago,&quot; Packer told the Associated Press.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Packer, 68, also will no longer call Atlantic Coast Conference games for Raycom. He said he was involved in an unspecified college basketball project and declined to speak of his legacy.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;I haven&apos;t spent, and don&apos;t anticipate spending, any time looking back,&quot; he said.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Packer became a magnet for controversy in recent years. He clashed with coach Phil Martelli after St. Joseph&apos;s received a No. 1 seed in the 2004 NCAA tournament and was generally regarded as an enemy of mid-major programs.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
He stood almost alone when he said Duke&apos;s Gerald Henderson was &quot;going for the ball&quot; when he bloodied the face of North Carolina&apos;s Tyler Hansbrough. And Packer disagreed with Kellogg, and seemingly everyone, when he insisted that Georgetown&apos;s Jeff Green had not traveled before hitting a game-winner against Vanderbilt.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The consummate contrarian, Packer did not carry a cell phone or use a computer. And though his knowledge of the game could not be questioned, most college basketball fans viewed him as a grumpy blowhard, not a charming throwback.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Deadspin.com called him &quot;Everybody&apos;s least favorite grandpa.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:tgreenstein@tribune.com&quot;&gt;tgreenstein@tribune.com&lt;/a&gt;</body>

	
	
	<categories>
	   <category>/sports/college</category>
	</categories>
</item>







    <item id="41012909" type="article">
	<title>Irish have an idea Watt to expect from recruit</title>
	<url>http://chicagosports.chicagotribune.com/sports/college/notredame/cs-080714-notre-dame-football-chris-watt,1,4016046.story</url>
	
    
	
        <byline>By Brian Hamilton</byline>
    
    
	
        <titleline>Chicago Tribune staff reporter</titleline>
    
    
	
        <date>2008-07-14</date>
        
        
            <time>21:12 -0500</time>
        
    
    
	<body>Last year, the Glenbard West football team employed an offensive strategy that was a bit odd, but wholly efficient. Whenever a key block was needed at tackle, guard or tight end, that&apos;s where they lined up Chris Watt.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
It was a flashing neon arrow that alerted the defense of the Hilltoppers&apos; intentions&amp;#8212;but was no help at all.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The No. 1 prospect in Illinois committed to play for Notre Dame last weekend.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;He&apos;s just a superior athlete,&quot; Glenbard West coach Chad Hetlet said. &quot;He&apos;s a very intelligent football player. That allows him to basically know every position on offense. And he just dominates the line of scrimmage.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 It wasn&apos;t his versatility per se that drew collegiate suitors to the senior-to-be. It&apos;s the athleticism that allows for the versatility, which will serve him well for his expected role on the Irish interior line.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;Right now I&apos;d be three-deep on the guard depth chart,&quot; Watt said. &quot;They&apos;re expecting me to work my tail off, and that&apos;s what I&apos;m expecting of myself.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;There are a lot of things I want to work on, because I mostly play tackle at the high school level. It&apos;s a different kind of technique.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
But it shouldn&apos;t be a stretch. Hetlet said Watt, even as he creeps toward 290 pounds, still has a 40-yard dash time in the 5-second realm. The 6-foot-3 Watt started on Glenbard West&apos;s varsity basketball team last season.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&quot;Honestly, I probably was as impressed with him on the basketball court as I was on the football field,&quot; recruiting analyst Tim O&apos;Halloran said. &quot;He can run like a guard. He can be a pulling guy if you need a pulling guy.&quot;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
 &amp;#8226;Former Lemont star and Notre Dame linebacker Aaron Nagel is transferring to Northwestern, the school announced Monday. Nagel did not play as a freshman and will sit out the 2008 season. His younger brother, Brett, is an incoming freshman with the Wildcats.</body>

	
	
	<categories>
	   <category>/sports/college/notredame</category>
	</categories>
</item>




</section>

</content>